我可以肯定地告诉你
I am telling you for sure
印尼人民党总理纳伦德拉 · 莫迪是印度总理候选人
that Gujarat CM Mr Narendra Modi is the BJP candidate for Prime Minister.
嘿，又发生了一起骗局
Hey, another scam has taken place.
奥古斯塔韦斯特兰
Augusta Westland.
教学大纲每年都在增加
Every year the syllabus increases, buddy.
人们反抗的原因是什么
What are the reasons for people's resistance
在印度引进茄子？
to the introduction of Bt Brinjal in India?
当然，几个世纪以来，印度拥有丰富的文化遗产
Of course, India has rich cultural heritage from centuries.
你怎么能这么说？
How can you even say that?
印度充满了性别歧视
India is full of gender discrimination.
这里，有堕除女胎，杀婴
Here, there is female foeticide, infanticide
在许多地区仍然盛行嫁妆
sati is still prevalent in many areas, dowry,
对妇女的暴力行为
violence against women
女性边缘化
'parda' tradition and women marginalization.
有数据和报告可以证实这一切
There is data and reports for it.
你怎么能说印度有丰富的文化呢？
How can you say that India has a rich culture?
妇女在整个世界被边缘化，不仅仅是在印度
Women are marginalized in the entire world and not just in India.
不要改变话题你说印度有丰富的文化，所以说服我吧
Don't change the topic. You said that India has rich culture so convince me.
- 证明给我看-你不会想被说服的
- Prove it to me. - You do not want to get convinced.
你太偏见了
You are too prejudiced.
你太消极了，阿比拉什
You are totally negative, Abhilash.
- 什么?-是的
- What? - Yes.
格里也这么说吗？
Even Guri says this?
- 你小时候就这样吗?-哈喽，哈喽
- Are you like this from childhood? - Hello, hello.
我根本不是认真的，我只是开玩笑
I was not at all serious. I was just joking.
所以你对我不是认真的？
So you are not serious with me?
对不起
Sorry.
现在就向她道歉
Apologize to her now.
你向我道歉
You apologize to me.
我们去吃“ Kulcha”(面包)吧
Let's go and have 'Kulcha' (bread).
你自己去吧
You go and eat Kulchas
- 嘿听我说-滚开白痴
- Hey, listen to me. - Get lost. Idiot.
嘿！
Hey!
你就不能道歉吗？
Couldn't you apologize?
你为什么这么怕她？
Why are you so scared of her?
我不怕她，我爱她
I am not scared of her. I love her.
对爱情不要太认真
Don't be serious about love.
因为爱情，让很多人留在这里，明白吗？
Because of their relationships, many people stayed back here. Understood?
她对研究非常认真，她会通过 UPSC 考试，但你不会
She is so serious about studies that she will clear UPSC but you will not.
我们可以把你的爱情告诉叔叔吗？
Shall we tell uncle about your love?
- 说真的让我告诉他吧-这不是开玩笑
- Seriously, let me tell him once. - This is not a joke.
你有没有告诉她我很消极？
Did you tell her that I am very negative?
你是我的朋友，所以试着去理解，我没有说任何负面的话
You are my friend so try to understand. I did not say anything negative.
她不是说他告诉她我是个消极的人吗？
Didn't she say that he told her that I am a negative person?
不不
No, no...
没有
No.
你笑什么？
Why are you laughing?
不，兄弟，安静点
No, buddy... Keep quiet.
要等20分钟左右，你可以告诉我你的名字和电话号码
There is 20 minutes of waiting. You can give me your name and number.
好吧
Okay.
20分钟太久了，我们改天再去见阿比拉什
20 minutes is too much. We will meet Abhilash some other time.
下次一定
When next.
我们决定今天见他，所以就一定要见到他
We had decided to meet him today so we will meet.
为什么你制造不必要的问题？
Why are you unnecessarily creating problems?
你要和你朋友的女朋友结婚
You are marrying your friend's girlfriend
你是说我在制造麻烦
and you are saying that I am creating a problem.
小声点
Speak softly.
请写信给我 Shwetketu Jha 998..
Please, write. Shwetketu Jha 998...
怎么写？
Which Ketu?
- Shwetketu，嘘... -
- Shwetketu, Sh... -
直接写SK也行
it is okay if you write SK.
搞定了，先生，Shwetketu Jha
It is done, sir. Shwetketu Jha.
好吧听着
Okay, listen...
官员马上就到
Mr Collector will be here soon.
给我们安排一张好桌子
Allot a good table to us
如果有任何问题，他会来这里进行突袭检查
and if there is any problem in service he will do a raid here.
突袭
Raid.
- 别担心兄弟-小心点
- Don't worry, brother. - Just be careful.
-好位置-走吧
- Nice table. - Let's go.
20分钟太久了
20 minutes is a long time.
你打算什么时候告诉我？
When were you thinking of telling me?
我正要告诉你
I was about to tell you.
然后你开始谈论普拉加蒂
And then you started talking about Pragati.
我想如果我现在发言，你一定会批判我
I thought if I will speak now then you will judge me.
我会批判你吗？
I will judge you?
我只是说有一天你会见到阿比拉什
I am just saying that someday you will meet Abhilash.
积极告诉他真相
Tell him the truth. Have a positive approach.
- SK-是的
- SK. - Yes.
在备考期间，我们之间没有什么
During preparation there was nothing between us.
海莉娅来卡纳尔是为了她的 NGO 工作
Dhairya had come to Karnal for her NGO work.
她在那里教书，她做得很好
She was teaching there. She was doing a good job.
我只是和她约会了2-3次然后... 你笑什么？
I just went out 2-3 times with her and then... why are you smiling?
你为什么要跟我解释？
Why are you explaining it to me?
你又没有做错什么
Are you doing something wrong?
你要结婚了，兄弟
You are getting married, buddy.
如果阿比拉什不接受怎么办？
What if Abhilash does not accept this?
如果他不接受，你就不结婚了吗？
Won't you get married if he does not accept?
你知道他会在餐馆里大吵大闹的
You know he will create a scene in the restaurant.
人不是一成不变的
People are not the same every time.
一切都会随着时间而改变
Everything changes with time.
海莉娅教得很好
Dhairya teaches well.
你看过她的讲座吗？
Do you watch her lectures?
在非学院，每个老师都互相观看对方的讲座
At Unacademy every teacher watches each other's lecture
让内容丰富起来
to make the content-rich.
海莉娅的互动现场是最好的
Dhairya's interactive live sessions are the best.
我通过观看她的讲座来准备我的教案
I prepare my study by watching her lectures
你应该给她打个电话
You should have called her.
我想打电话给她，但不知道你的情况
I was thinking to call her but did not know your scene as well.
起来，兄弟
Get up, brother.
你都已经5天没来送报纸了
For the last 5 days, you have not delivered Hindu.
我不得不花钱去买
I have to buy to read it.
我们不读《经济时报》就不能拉屎
We cannot pass stool without reading Economic Times.
在过去的五天里，我一直便秘
And I am experiencing constipation it for the last five days.
你知道我怎么了吗？
Do you know what happened to me?
我的自行车在这里滑倒了，脚扭伤了
My cycle slipped here and my foot got sprained.
路上坑坑洼洼的，我该怎么办？
There are so many potholes. What can I do?
你应该小心
You should be careful.
月球上也有坑洞，人类也到过那里
There are potholes on the moon as well. Man has reached there as well.
这些坑坑洼洼都会被填平，我们的国家是伟大的
These potholes will be filled. Our country is great.
我们的国家并不伟大
Our country is not great.
除了污染和人口，我们给世界带来了什么？
What have we given the world except for pollution and population?
我们以任何方式对科学和技术作出了贡献吗？
Have we contributed in any way to science and technology?
我们发明了零
We have invented Zero.
这是我们唯一给予的东西
That is the only thing we have given.
马诺基 · 库马尔为此写了一首歌，这就是我们一直在唱的
Manoj Kumar made a song of it and that is what we have been singing.
除此之外呢？
Other than that?
我们做了灯泡，飞机了吗
Have we made bulb, airplane
电视，冰箱，互联网，手机,
TV, fridge, internet, mobile,
扑热息痛和这个牙刷？
paracetamol and this brush?
这些是我们做的吗？
Have we made this?
亲爱的，没有这些物质的东西，我们仍然可以快乐
Dear, we can still be happy without these materialistic things.
我们已经通过灵性展示了通往世界的道路
We have shown the path to the world through spirituality.
你住在哪个世界，叔叔？
In which world do you stay, uncle?
在印度有人快乐吗? 告诉我
Is anyone happy in India? Tell me.
有一个叫做幸福报告的东西
There is something called Happiness Report.
在157个国家中，我们排在第118位
Among 157 countries we are at 118th number.
我们在排放二氧化碳排名第二
And we are at 2nd number in releasing carbon dioxide.
平均寿命是145
Life expectancy is 145
读写能力168
literacy at 168
在人类发展指数中，我们排在第135位
and in Human Development Index we are at 135th number.
看，我们国家也发生了这么多好事，不是吗？
Look, so many good things are also happening in our country. Isn't it?
我们的国家很好
Our country is very good.
为自己是印度人而骄傲
Be proud to be an Indian.
不，叔叔，我不是一个骄傲的印度人
No uncle, I am not a proud Indian.
你为什么想成为 IAS？
Why do you want to become an IAS?
你一直在批评
You are criticizing all the time.
没有，先生，我也写了解决方案
No, sir. I have written solutions as well.
看了这些之后，我觉得你写的答案只是为了解决而解决
Reading these I feel you have written answers just for the sake of it.
你只是写了解决方案，因为你被要求这样做
You just wrote the solutions because you were asked to do so.
在你所有的回答中都缺少积极的方法
Positive approach is missing in all your answers.
看这，你已经拒绝了
Look, you have simply rejected that
辛格政府的 Aadhaar 法案
Aadhaar Yojna of Manmohan Singh's government.
因为我觉得
Because I think
法案执行之后，那么人们的隐私就有危险
Aadhaar becomes prevalent then the privacy of people is at risk.
所以你的解决方案就是不去实施它
So your solution is not to implement it.
试着去理解将会发生什么
Just try to understand what will happen
如果下届政府通过 Aadhaar 法案？
if the next government passes the Aadhaar bill?
你的解决方案应该是尽量减少隐私问题
Your approach should have been as to how to minimize privacy issues.
我们怎样才能使它对人们来说值得信赖？
How can we make it trustworthy for people?
作为一个公务员，你应该用积极的方法找到解决方案
As an IAS you are expected to find solutions with a positive approach.
明白了吗年轻人
Understood, young man.
在过去的65年里，我们一直保持着积极的态度
We have been keeping a positive approach for the last 65 years.
巴基斯坦变了吗？
Has Pakistan changed?
你需要实际一点
You need to be practical.
所有这些听起来都很好，但没有什么能因此得到解决
All these things are good to hear but nothing gets solved because of this.
你和那个有什么关系？
What have you to do with that?
按考官要求的方式回答问题
Answer in the way the examiner wants.
如果你做不到，那就假装
If you cannot do it then fake it?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你听说过尼尔马尔·库马尔吗？
Have you heard about Nirmal Kumar?
你是说奥迪萨干部
You mean the Odisha Cadre one.
我发誓他的采访非常有名
I swear his interview is very famous.
在达夫，他把下棋当作一种爱好
In DAF he had taken chess as a hobby.
但他对国际象棋一无所知
And he knew nothing about chess.
他在一次采访中被问到这个问题
He was asked about it in an interview.
他把特级大师决赛选手的每一个动作都打乱了
He had mugged up each move of each finalist of grandmaster.
还是老样子
The same.
他在采访中非常自信
He was so confident in the interview.
似乎世界上没有人比他更了解象棋了
It seemed as if no one knew chess better than him in the world.
没有人会在意你的真实想法
No one is damn bothered about what you think in real.
所以一直装到你成功
So fake it till you make it.
不管怎样，通过考试是很重要的
Anyways it is important to clear the exam.
我可以为此做任何事
I can do anything for that.
[电视远声音]
[TV Playing at a distance]
这就是为什么我们想成为一个政府官员
That is why we want to be an IAS.
在印度没有比这更安全的工作了
There is no other job safer than this in India.
政府能做的就是把你调走，但不会解雇你
What the state can do is to transfer you but not fire you.
有了这样的工作保障，每个人都能很高兴地为国家服务
A person will happily serve the nation when you have such job security.
我的梦想是..
My dream is to...
今天我不打算饶了这糟老头子
I am not going to spare this old man today.
嘿，要我和你一起去吗？
Hey, shall I come with you?
什么事
Yes.
叔叔，你答应过我电视只会开一段时间
Uncle, you had told me that TV will be on for some time
而今天却开了一整天
and now it remains on an entire day.
我要离开这个房间了，叔叔
I will leave the room, uncle.
走吧，马上搬走
Leave it. Leave it immediately.
你是在帮我吗？
Are you doing me a favour?
这里很便宜，所以你才住在这里
It is cheap so that is why you are staying here.
如果你连礼貌都没有，怎么成为政府官员？
How will you become an IAS when you do not have the manners to talk?
印度和其他亚洲国家之间的贸易协定
'The trade deal between India and other Asian countries.'
辛格总理对此表示高兴
'PM Manmohan Singh expressed happiness.'
怎么回事？
What is going on?
我一直在给你打电话，我以为你逃跑了
I was trying to call you. I thought you escaped.
洗手间外面有一排醉汉
There was a queue of drunkard outside the washrooms.
因为政府官员不守时
As it is government officials are not punctual.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
来了
There...
拿着，谢谢
Take this. Thank you.
你好吗，兄弟？
How are you, brother?
你长胖了
You have put on weight.
-格里让你吃太多黄油了吗?-没有，兄弟
- Has Guri made you eat too much butter? - No, buddy.
所有这些都是他的辛勤工作
All this is his hard work.
格里，你好吗？
How are you, Guri?
来吧
Come.
先生，您的桌子准备好了
Dhoomketu sir, your table is ready.
该死..
Shwet...
我们走，快点，我们走
Let's go. Come on let's go.
- 你好吗?-你往前走我跟着你
- How are you? - You move ahead and I will follow you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
请签字
Please, sign.
我刚在会员表上签了字
I just signed the membership form.
记在账本上
Do it in the register.
你必须记下你到达和离开的时间
You have to make an entry about your arrival and departure time.
让我先来
Let me first come.
嗨
Hi.
你经常来图书馆学习吗？
Do you often come to the library to study?
不，我只是在跟踪你
No. I was just following you.
哦！
Oh!
我从前面看起来更帅
I look more handsome from the front.
哦，该死
Oh shit.
坏了吗？
Has it broken?
看起来是坏了
Yes. Seems to be.
对不起，我真的很抱歉，我会把它修好的
Sorry. I am really sorry. I will get it repaired.
不，没关系
No, it's okay.
不会花很多时间的，附近有一家眼镜店
It will not take much time. There is a shop close by.
我只是整理了一下书，没有看到那副眼镜，真的很抱歉
I just kept the books and did not see the spectacles. I am really sorry.
- 没事的-安静
- It's okay. - Quiet.
我们在图书馆外面
Now we are standing outside.
我有铁路考试
I have my railways exam.
那你为什么要这么做？
Then why did you do it?
我能怎么办? 他们不准备退还费用
What could I do? They were not ready to refund the fees.
你告诉我，生活中有没有什么重要的事情可以让你成为一个 IAS？
You tell me. Is there anything important in life to become an IAS?
有的
There is.
什么？
What?
螺丝钉在那儿，但是不合适
The screw is there but it isn't fitting.
边框断了，你得重新做一个
Its threading has broken. You will have to get a new one made.
好吧，再做一个
Okay, make a new one.
不用了，我一会儿去做，没问题的
Leave it. I will get it made later. There is no problem.
我把它弄坏了，如果你选一个便宜的也没关系，但是你必须戴着眼镜走
I broke it. It is okay if you take a cheap one but you will have to take it.
没事的，海莉娅
Leave it, Dhairya.
看一下镜框
Show the new one.
我已经把准备好了
I have already taken it out.
男生可能会拒绝，但在与女朋友的争论中不会赢
Sir might refuse but cannot win in an argument with his girlfriend.
她不是我的女朋友
She is not my girlfriend.
她是你妹妹吗？
Is she your sister?
你在说什么? 你没有礼貌吗？
What are you saying? Don't you have manners?
为什么是兄妹？
Why sister?
你说什么都行，有点礼貌吧
You are just saying anything. Have some manners.
对不起，是好朋友
Sorry. Close friend.
是的
Yes...
试试这个
Try this one.
我不戴无边框的眼睛，它很容易碎
I don't wear frameless. It breaks easily.
至少试一次
At least try it once.
好吧
Okay fine.
Okay.
现在你从前面看起来很帅
Now you are looking handsome from the front.
我告诉你，面试中戴着这副眼镜
I am telling you that you will get one mark extra
你会多得一分
because of this frame in the interview.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
当然
Sure.
这个是加糖的
This one is with sugar.
哦! 我一定是拿错了
Oh! I think it got exchanged.
-你喝这个-不，没关系
- Take this one. - No, it is fine.
我已经喝了一小口，我会喝完的
I have already taken a sip so will have it.
只是你喝了一小口
It is just that you have taken a sip.
它没有毒，我喝这个
It has not become poisonous. I will have it.
没关系
It is okay.
你已经开始预备考试的复习了吗？
Have you started the revision for the prelims?
什么？
What?
是的
Yes.
不，不，还不知道怎么作答
No, no the fight for answer writing is going on.
所以我还没有开始
So I have not started yet.
参加这个测试系列，这样你就可以练习更多
Join the test series so you will able to practice more.
你练习多长时间？
How much do you practice?
- 我每天一定要解决一个问题-这样啊
- I solve one paper for sure every day. - Okay.
要么9点-12点，要么2点到5点
Either 9 to 12 or sometimes 2 to 5.
很好 UPSC 时间
Nice. UPSC time.
哇! 真不错
Wow! Very nice.
非常好
Very nice.
我有个请求
I have a request.
这对我的复习也有帮助
This will help in my practice as well.
完成了吗？
Done?
你一定认为我是个哑巴
You must be thinking that I am dumb.
你应该永远和那些和你平等的人做朋友
You should always be friends with the ones who are equal to you.
我学校的前男友也很蠢，现在他是个飞行员
The ex-boyfriend of my school was also dumb and today he is a pilot.
还有幸福的婚姻
And happily married. Lol.
为什么前男友能享受所有的乐趣？
Why should ex-boyfriends have all the fun?
让我们再写一篇论文，开心一下
Let's write another paper and have fun.
你有自己的房间
You have your own room.
不用合租，但你还是来图书馆学习
No sharing and still you come to the library to study.
你在这两个地方都在浪费钱
You are wasting money at both places.
我过去常在这个房间里学习
I used to study in the room
但是房东电视的声音让我很不安
but the sound of TV disturbed me.
我向叔叔抱怨，他让我离开房间
I complained to my uncle and he asked me to leave the room.
搬走吧
Leave it.
什么？
What?
告诉我，生活中有什么重要的事情要让你成为 IAS 吗
Tell me is there anything important in life to become IAS.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
你知道，在纳加尔租一个房间并不容易
You are very well aware that it is not easy to get a room in Rajinder Nagar.
那么为什么要付出努力
So why put in the effort.
所以这就是分数低的原因
So this is the reason for low marks.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我觉得你对生活有一种消极的态度
I felt that you have a negative approach towards life.
你一直在限制自己
You keep cribbing.
纸张没有完成，你不要尝试新的框架
Paper did not get complete, you don't want to try new frames
我是哑巴，所以没有朋友..
and I am dumb so no friends...
我认为这种方法在你的回答中也是可见的
I think this approach is visible in your answers as well.
所以，你也认为我是一个消极的人
So, even you think I am a negative person.
不，我总是看到积极的一面
No. I always look at the positive side.
从此以后
And henceforth
你也应该看看
you should also see it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
等一下，我送了你礼物，所以我的名字应该写在这里
One minute. I have gifted you so my name should be written here.
如果生活中没有任何事情发生
If nothing in life happens according to you
那你应该改变你的方法
then you should change your approach.
我想如果你考不过UPSC，那么你可以试试PCS
I thought that if you couldn't clear UPSC then you will try for PCS.
我喜欢教书，这是我的工作类型
I am enjoying teaching. It is my type of work.
我真的从我以前写的诗中受益匪浅
I am really benefitting from the poetry I used to write.
我的三个学生获得了非学院的奖学金
Three of my students have won scholarship from Unacademy Combat.
是的
Yes.
你教过他们？
You have taught them?
是的，我教过他们，去和学生们谈一谈
Yes, I have taught them. Go and talk to the students once.
非学院的教育工作者是最棒的
The educator of Unacademy is good.
前政府官员教学这对学生很有帮助
Ex IAS and bureaucrats teach. It is very helpful for students.
一个是纳迪普 · 甘地，另一个是梅加纳 · 索曼，还有一个是尼尚 · 雷迪
One is Navdeep Gandhi, another one is Meghana Soman and one is Nishant Reddy.
他们真的教得很好
They really teach well.
他们教得好吗？
Do they teach well?
他们是教的好还是教的很好？
Do they good or very good?
非常好，但我也是我的学科最好的
Very good but I am also best in my subject. Best.
当然我过去常常在非学院上看你所有的视频课程
Of course. I used to watch all your video classes on Unacademy.
看，他看了我的视频
Look, he watches my videos.
他看了我的视频，但不会满足一次保持他的自尊心
He will watch the video but will not come to meet once keeping his ego aside.
我没有你那样的养老金和奢侈
I do not have a pension and luxury as you have.
责任比奢侈和舒适更重要，我的朋友
There are more responsibilities than luxury and comfort, my friend.
好的，兄弟
Right, brother.
像格里这样的商人最享受奢华和舒适，不是吗？
Businessmen like Guri enjoy luxury and comfort the most. Isn't it?
商人？
Businessman?
他制作高仿的鞋子
He makes duplicate shoes.
别瞎说，我那不是高仿，是原创的
Rascal, I don't make duplicate but local ones.
HIKE 是我公司的名字，在亚马逊选择网站上也有
HIKE is the name of my company and it is there on Amazon Choice.
如果你想的话..
If you want then...
- 什么?-HIKE
- What? - Hike...
耐克..
Nike...
耐克... 海克…
Nike... Hike...
他正在通过创造就业机会来做真正的事情
He is doing the real thing by generating employment.
我们的国家限制最需要这个，不是吗？
As of now, our country needs this the most. Isn't it?
在任何社会中，教师的地位都是最高的
In any society the position of the teacher is uppermost.
正确地说，上师梵天，上师毗湿奴，上师马赫什瓦拉..
It is rightly said that Guru Brahma, Guru Vishnu, Guru Maheshwara...
完全正确，但是只有政府官员在社会上是自由的
Absolutely right. Only IAS are sitting free in society.
兄弟，你..
Buddy, you...
先生，你想要点什么？
Sir, what would you like to have?
告诉他你要说的话，否则我会扇你耳光
Tell him what you wanted to say otherwise I will slap you.
发生了什么？
What happened?
他想告诉你一些事
He wanted to tell you something.
我是说我们是骑自行车来的
I was saying that we have come by bike.
所以如果我们喝酒骑车，警察会抓住我们的
So police will catch hold of us if we drink and ride.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
我们这么多年没见
We are meeting after so many years.
一定要喝到吐不出来才行
We will keep drinking till we do not puke.
兄弟..
Brother...
这次是格里的婚礼
It is Guri's wedding.
阿比拉什没有变，一点也没变
Abhilash has not changed. Not changed at all.
那么格里，是你的家庭安排了这段婚姻，还是一段爱情婚姻？
So Guri, did your family fix the marriage or it is a love marriage?
这是爱情婚姻，他..
It is a love marriage. He...
- 让我说完-好的
- Let me speak. - Yes.
这是一场爱情婚姻
It is a love marriage.
你的未婚妻是做什么的？
What does your fiancé do?
她经营着一家非政府组织
She runs an NGO.
非政府组织是做什么的？
What does the NGO do?
它以未成年人为目标
It targets children.
我的意思是他们帮助孩子们摆脱毒品的习惯
I mean they help children get rid of their habit of drugs.
太好了，伙计，你做得太棒了
Great, buddy. You are doing an amazing job.
我会支持你们的
I will support you people.
你的未婚妻应该是 IAS
Your fiancé should have been an IAS.
她叫什么名字？
What is her name?
我想去洗手间
I want to go to the washroom.
继续坐着
Keep sitting.
什么？
What?
喝点水再走
Drink some water and then go.
喝了它
Drink it.
您的饮料，先生
Drinks for you, sir.
格里
Guri
我真的很抱歉，伙计..
I am really sorry buddy...
无论我们之间发生了什么
for whatever happened between us.
在过去的六年里
It is not that SK and Guri that
我一直都在想念你们
I did not miss you in the last six years.
你一定在想，在成为政府官员之后
You must be thinking that after becoming an IAS
我一定是变了，但事实并非如此
I must have changed but that is not the case.
我有点傻
I was a bit stupid.
我为我们之间发生的一切感到抱歉
I am sorry for whatever that happened between us.
让我们结束这场战斗，忘记这一切吧
Let's finish the fight. Let's forget that.
就在今晚，兄弟
Let's finish it tonight, buddy.
我很高兴你邀请了我
I am very happy that you invited me.
我们是兄弟，我们三个
We are brothers. Three of us.
原谅我，兄弟
Forgive me, buddy.
对不起
I am sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
以格里新生命的名义
In the name of Guri's new life.
以嫂子的名义
In the name of sister-in-law.
格普瑞特 · 辛格的婚礼
Gurpreet Singh weds...
海莉娅..
Dhairya...
看，海雅送给我这个
Look, Dhairya gifted me this.
非常好
Very nice.
这件衣服也很适合我，我要留着吗？
It is suiting me as well. Shall I keep it?
不要用邪恶的眼光看别人的东西
Don't put an evil eye on other's things.
占有欲这么强？
So possessive?
一旦 SK 知道了海莉娅和你的事，他就会批评你
SK will set you right once he comes to know about Dhairya and you.
她是一个非常好的女孩，我从她身上感受到了良好的气氛
She is a very nice girl. I get good vibes from her.
- 瓦利亚叔叔来了-靠边停车
- Here comes Walia uncle. - Get aside. Stop the rickshaw here.
- 小心停车-带我去
- Stop here carefully. - Show me.
太棒了! 你把达莉娅划掉改成了海莉娅
Great! You have written Dhairya after cutting Dahiya.
小心地把你的脚放下
Carefully put your foot down.
- 你真聪明-拿着
- You are so clever. - Take it.
小心，小心..
Careful, careful...
- 过来-发生什么事了？
- Come. - What happened?
发生了什么？
What happened?
我只是想改变我的方法
I am just trying to change my approach.
叔叔，需要帮忙吗
Uncle, may I help you?
我不需要你的帮助
I don't need your help.
早上很粗鲁，现在想做个好人
Rude in the morning and now trying to be good.
抓住我的手，来
Hold my hand. Come.
这边
This way.
好吧，别管考官的标准了
Okay, forget the examiner's standard.
我们一起写答题，互相检查对方的答案
We'll write answer sheets together and will check each other's copies.
好
Okay.
我们会根据我们对对方的回答印象如何而给分数
We will give marks according to how we get impressed with each other's answers.
你怎么说？
What do you say?
-我觉得很好-是吗？
- Works for me. - Works?
是的
Yes.
阿姨在吗？
Is aunty there?
她刚吃完药睡着
She has just slept after taking medicine.
这是我给她买的
I got these for her.
117？
117?
我觉得你给我的分数太高了
I think you have given me too many marks.
顶级考生才能得到这样的分数
Toppers score such marks.
61? 你给我评分不及格
61? You failed me.
不，我没有..
No, I did not...
哦，不，我把 Laxmikant (书)忘在里面了我马上回来
Oh no, I forgot Laxmikant (book) inside. I will just be back.
拿着这些钱走吧
Take this money and leave.
快走快走
Go, go...leave quickly.
怎么了? 人力车去哪儿了？
What happened? Where did the rickshaw go?
他不在这儿，我想他已经走了
He was not here. I think he has left.
那我们去散步吧
Let's go walking then.
我们去散步好吗？
Shall we go walking?
为了打击恐怖主义，英联邦应该孤立巴基斯坦
To fight terrorism Commonwealth should isolate Pakistan.
你认真的吗？
Seriously?
作为一名外交官，你应该鼓励希望
As a diplomat, you should promote hope.
印度和巴基斯坦应该考虑英联邦，而不是视其为障碍
Rather than a hurdle, India and Pakistan must view commonwealth
作为联合打击恐怖主义和解决分歧的媒介
as a medium to jointly combat terror and resolve differences.
这种充满希望的方法将对南盟其他组织产生积极影响
And this hopeful approach will have positive impact on other SAARC forums.
她去洗澡了
She slipped into the bathroom.
你可以明天去见她-好的
You can meet her tomorrow. -Okay.
在案例研究中，你可以让考官有点情绪化
You can make the examiner a little emotional in case studies.
你把语言组织得很好
You structure things very well.
你的问题只是缺少练习和正确的方法
Just less practice and right approach are your problems.
不管你知不知道答案，留下一个问题就是自杀
You know the answer or not but leaving one question is suicide.
开始倾听积极的自我肯定
Start listening to positive affirmations.
7-5-3答案写作法则
7-5-3 rule of answer writing.
在7分钟内完成每个答案
Finish each answer in 7 minutes.
写5个与关键词相关的点
Write 5 points related to keyword
然后在三维空间中详细描述每个点
and then elaborate each point in 3 dimensions.
你现在一定觉得我是个哑巴
You must be feeling now that I am dumb.
你好，叔叔
Hello uncle.
给阿姨买的水果
For aunty.
为什么每天都要拿这些东西给我们？
What is the need to getting these things every day?
叔叔，我才送了八九次，不是每天都送的
Uncle, I have just got things 8-9 times. This is not every day.
我只是来见阿姨，阿姨在吗？
I just came to meet aunty. Is aunty there?
卫生间？
Bathroom?
不，亲爱的
No, dear.
我的脚在外面的坑洞里扭伤了
My foot got twisted in the pothole outside.
路上坑坑洼洼的，谁也不管
There are so many potholes on the road and no one does anything.
你一定很痛苦，阿姨
You must be in real pain, aunty.
我们现在能做什么？
What can we do now?
古吉拉特邦首席部长莫迪将于12月27日访问德里
'Gujarat's chief minister Mr. Modi will come to Delhi on 27th Dec'
成为 Rashtriya Vikas Parishad 的一员
'to be a part of Rashtriya Vikas Parishad.'
你儿子住在哪里，阿姨? 我从没见过他
Where does your son stay, aunty? I have never seen him.
他在日本
He stays in Japan.
好吧
Okay.
大学毕业后，他去那里培训，然后在那里找到了一份工作
After college, he went there for training and then he got a job there.
你去过那里吗？
Have you ever gone there?
你在这里一定感到孤独
You must be feeling lonely here.
我们去过那里一次
We had gone there once
却无法适应那里
but could not adjust there.
所以我们回来了
So we came back.
他因为工作原因不能回家
He cannot come here because of his job.
我已经三年没有见到他了
It has been three years since I last saw him.
[电视新闻播放]
[News playing on TV]
阿姨，有什么需要就给我打电话，什么都行
Aunty, you can call me whenever you need anything. Anything.
我每天都会来见你
I will come every day to meet you.
阿姨，你说得对
Aunty, you are right.
为什么要去另一个国家？
Why should you go to another country?
我们的国家很好
Our country is nice.
你在那里无法适应
You will not be able to adjust there.
你在这里很好
You are fine here.
叔叔说的没错，只有发明不能使一个国家变得伟大
Uncle is right in saying that only inventions do not make a country great
是人们让国家变得伟大
but it is people who make it great.
和像你这样永不放弃希望的人在一起
With people like you who never leave hope.
你说得对
You are right.
你为什么不把电视移到另一个房间呢？
Listen, why don't you shift the TV to another room?
现在我只能坐着看
I just have to sit and watch.
我在哪看都是一样，不应该打扰他学习
So I will sit there. His studies should not get disturbed.
我们可以坐在任何地方观看
We can sit and watch anywhere.
不，阿姨，没关系，如果你把电视移到另一个房间
No aunty. It is fine. If you shift the TV to another room
然后其他人就会受到干扰
then someone else will get disturbed.
谁会被打扰? 没有人会被打扰
Who will get disturbed? No one will get disturbed.
前几天我告诉他把电视搬到另一个房间去
The other day I told him to shift the TV to another room.
他不听，他只是懒惰
He does not listen. He is just lazy.
你听到了吗? 把电视移到另一个房间
Did you listen? Shift the TV to another room.
够了
Enough of it now.
是的，瓦利亚叔叔只是太懒了
Yes. Walia uncle was just being lazy.
想象一下，这么多年来，有多少有抱负的人被电视困扰
Just imagine how many aspirants must be in trouble for last so many years.
但我成功地给阿姨留下了深刻的印象
But I was successful in impressing aunty.
嘿... 这边
Hey...this way.
什么？
What?
所以你已经解决了这个问题
So you have solved the problem.
现在你没有理由去图书馆了
Now you will not come to the library.
现在去图书馆的理由更多了
Now there are more reasons to come to the library.
再见-再见
Bye. -Bye.
“这是巧合吗? 见到你?”
"Is this a coincidence? To meet you?"
“时间无所谓”
"Time is regardless"
“我开始不顾一切地跟踪你”
"I started following you regardless of anything."
“一切都变得无关紧要了”
"Everything has become regardless."
“有各种各样的理由让人坐立不安，惊讶不已”
"There are all the reasons for restlessness, surprises"
“耻辱和许多故事”
"Disgrace and many stories."
“遇见你之后，我的生活变得光明起来”
"My life has brightened after I met you."
“你就像我心中的一盏明灯”
"You are like a light in me."
“我喜欢你的纯真，你一直在我的脑海里”
"I like your innocence and you are in my thoughts all the time."
“你就像我心中的一朵云”
"You are like a cloud in me."
“我想在你的庇护所里淋湿”
"I want to get drenched in your shelter."
“不管发生什么，我都想留下来”
"I want to stay back regardless of everything."
“我想要流动
"I want to flow
“不管发生什么，我都想死”
"I want to die regardless of everything."
我们害怕你会有什么反应
We were scared as to how you would react.
这件事已经过去六年了
This matter is six years old.
格里，我真的很开心
Guri, I am actually happy.
不要想太多
Don't think too much.
我们在纳加尔短暂的时光，关系又能走多远呢？
Do you very well know where the relationships of Rajinder Nagar go?
谁会当回事？
Who takes them seriously?
现在她是我的嫂子，格里
Now she is my sister-in-law, Guri.
我已经有六年没和她说过话了
And it has been six years since I spoke to her.
兄弟，现在我要喝酒了
Buddy, now I will drink alcohol.
他一直给我添麻烦
He has been troubling me a lot.
告诉我一件事
Tell me one thing.
你以为除了她没有别的女孩进入我的生活吗？
Do you think that no other girl came into my life after her?
对此我们能说什么呢？
What can we say about this?
太神奇了
Amazing.
服务员..
Waiter...
我现在就点菜
I will order now.
- 不，我来 -
- No, I will do it. -
先来三箱啤酒
Get three Old Monk.
不，等等，你的特别饮料是什么？
No, wait. What is your special drink?
先生，这里的一切都很特别
Sir, here everything is special.
一切都很特别
Everything is special.
- 把菜单给我-好的，先生
- Then get me the menu. - Yes sir.
- 阿比拉什...-等一下
- Abhilash... - One second.
我来，让我点菜吧
I will do it. Let me order.
菜单给我
Give it to me.
这次保证再也不会出现裂痕
Fill the pothole in such a way that it does not break again.
先生，这么少的钱和材料，我们不可能建成一条高速公路
Sir, in so less money and material, we will not be able to make an expressway.
这不是你的工作
It is not your job.
你在浪费时间我们走吧我们要迟到了
You are just wasting time. Let's go. We are getting late.
你知道，官员考试不是从国家行政学院开始的
You know the training of IAS does not begin from LBSNAA
而是从他开始为 UPSC 做准备开始的
but from the time he starts preparation for UPSC.
嘿，不要谈论哲学
Hey, don't talk about philosophy
而是集中精力准备考试
but instead concentrate on clearing the exam.
这不是哲学，而是与考试有关
It is not about philosophy but the exam.
我总是有一个问题
I always had one problem.
我过去常常抄袭每个问题，对吧？
I used to crib on every problem. Right?
- 是的-没错
- Yes. - Correct.
每个人过去都认为我是消极的
And everyone used to feel that I am negative. And this is negative.
但是，只要有积极的态度，我就可以把它变成行动
But with a positive approach I can turn it into actions
然后得到积极的结果
and then into positive results.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
你明白我在说什么吗？
Do you understand what I am saying?
不明白
No.
听着，我会解释的
Look, I will explain.
我对自己做了个案研究，我意识到
I did a case study on myself and I realized
我总能找出问题所在
that I could always identify the problem.
是的，但这还不够
Yes. But that is not enough.
如果我要成为一名政府官员，那么我必须更进一步
If I have to become IAS then I have to take a step further.
我必须解决这些问题
I will have to solve those problems.
只有这样，事情才会改变，制度才会改变
Only then things will change, system will change.
只有这样，官僚主义的目的才能得到解决
Only then the purpose of bureaucracy will be solved.
但是，做这一切的动机从何而来？
But from where will the motivation to do all this come?
告诉我
Tell me.
所以现在我们可以看到积极的结果方法
So here comes into the picture the positive approach towards results.
通过对瓦利亚叔叔进行实验，我明白了这一点
I understood this by experimenting with Walia uncle.
积极的方法可以改变一些事情
A positive approach changes things.
你错了，格里
You are wrong Guri.
我不能在考试中假装，也不能在面试中假装
I can't fake it in exams. I can't or in an interview.
这种态度应该在我体内
that attitude should be inside me.
如果积极的态度存在于我的个性中
If positive approach is there in my personality
那么它一定会在考试中大放异彩
then it will definitely shine in the exam.
我现在完全明白了为什么我想成为一名政府官员
I have now completely understood that why I want to be an IAS.
为什么？
Why?
因为我有潜力
Because I have the potential.
我可以带来改变
I can bring about a change.
有人想带来积极的改变，这并不特别
It is not special that someone wants to bring a positive change.
但特别的是，他带来了积极的变化
But the special thing is that he brings about a positive change.
看，这就是改变，路面的坑已经填满了
See, this is the change. The pothole is filled.
这是我们成为官员后必须做的事情
This is what we have to do after becoming IAS.
我们不应该在纸面上解决问题，而必须在实际中解决问题
We do not have to solve the problems on paper but the ground.
你做这一切只是在浪费时间
You are just wasting your time by doing all this.
在这里一定没有其他傻瓜像你一样
There must be no other fool in Rajinder Nagar as you are.
- 还很聪明-什么？
- And smart too. - What?
- 他在错误的时间说了正确的话-是的
- He is saying it at the wrong time but whatever he is saying is right. - Yes.
走吧，我们要迟到了，普拉加蒂一定在等我们
Let's go. We are getting late. Pragati must be waiting.
我们走
Let's go.
为什么佩马发送他的说唱收藏家萨博集团？
Why does Pema send his rap on Collector Saab Group?
这个小组是用来分享笔记的
This group was made for sharing notes.
桑迪普，你一定可以带来改变
Sandeep, you can surely bring about a change.
如果你把它带到这个男孩身上，那么你也可以把它带到社会上来
If you have brought it in this boy then you can bring it in society as well.
案例研究的结论是，你正在成为一名政府官员
The conclusion of the case study is that you are becoming an IAS.